Neufeld, Maurice Papers /3007
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series I. CORRESPONDENCE/ADMINISTRATIVE FILES
  - Research, 1962-1966 (Box 25, Folder 15-18)
    Research proposals and routine correspondence. Includes newspaper clippings
  - Research, 1967-1969 (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - Research - Bayberry, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    Paper and routine correspondence.
  - Research - Clippings, 1966-1976 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Research - Copyright, 1950-1977 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Research Club of Cornell University, 1954-1969 (Box 25, Folder 24-26)
    Membership lists and routine correspondence
  - Resident Instruction Office, 1962-1980 (Box 25, Folder 27-29)
  - Review - ILR, 1946-1969 (Box 25, Folder 30-33)
    Corres re MFN's editing and routine correspondence.
  - Richardson, Reed C. (former Ph.D. student) -Correspondence, 1953-1977 (Box 25, Folder 34-36)
    Exams, papers, and routine correspondence.
  - Rothstein, William (former Ph.D. student) - Correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    Exams and routine correspondence
  - Rotondaro, Ruben (former M.S. student) - Correspondence, 1964-1976 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Ryan, Patricia (former M.S. student) - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    Routine correspondence. Thesis abstract, exams, and routine correspondence. Includes newspaper clippings
  - Schramm, LeRoy (former Ph.D. student) - Correspondence, 1968-1979 (Box 25, Folder 40-42)
    Papers, exams, and routine correspondence
  - Society of Professionals in Dispute Resolution, 1972-1978 (Box 25, Folder 43-44)
  - Spanish Affairs, 1964-1966 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Speakers, 1945-1977 (Box 26, Folder 2-5)
  - State University, 1951-1978 (Box 26, Folder 6-8)
  - State University - Council on Graduate Study, 1951-1968 (Box 26, Folder 9-12)
    Corres from Alvin C. Eurich, SUNY president, to MFN re the appointment of MFN to serve on the council [5/28/51], reports, and routine correspondence. Includes newspaper clippings
  - Student Activity, 1946-1980 (Box 26, Folder 13-16)
    General memo to faculty re SCARB (Scheduling, Coordination and Activities Review Board) ruling on Students for Democratic Society (SDS) activities [4/5/67], minutes of University Faculty meeting [3/5/67], memo from MFN to Provost Corson re a proposal to institutionalize student protest at Cornell by providing arbitration and student ombudsmen [11/23/66], corres from MFN to SCARB informing them he is not continuing as Faulty Advisor for the SDS C9/20/65], routine corres re MFN's involvement with the Seminar to Analyze Selected Aspects of American Society [Held 4/20/64], and other routine correspondence. Assorted pamphlets, letters, and newspaper clippings by and about student political and educational reform organizations
  - Student Activity - Watermargin, 1947-1971 (Box 26, Folder 17-19)
    Cornell living unit and organization open to men of all races, religions and creeds. Corres from MFN to John Marcham, Chairman of the Board of Directors, indicating his resignation from the Watermargin Board [2/20/50], and other routine correspondence, pamphlets and reports detailing the creation of Watermargin. Includes newspaper clippings
  - Student Applications - Other Schools, 1955-1976 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    Routine correspondence and letters of recommendation. Removed and restricted.
  - Student Conduct, 1963-1968 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    reports on campus codes and routine correspondence
  - Student - ILR - Alumni - General, 1955-1980 (Box 26, Folder 22-23)
    Memo re effort to organize union at a Virgin Islands hotel [9/21/76], reports, booklets, and routine correspondence concerning ILR alumni activities. Includes newspaper clippings
  - Student Placement, 1957-1972 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    Resumes and routine correspondence. Includes newspaper clippings.
  - Students - ILR - Alumni - Founder's Project, 1975-1978 (Box 26, Folder 25-28)
    Established by ILR alumni, the Founder's Project commemorates 30th anniversary of NYSSILR by honoring the original faculty members of the Dept. of Collective Bargaining, Labor Law, and Labor History and providing a framework to launch a fundraising drive. Routine correspondence re MFN's coordination of the Founder's Project Seminar [12/3/75], copies of papers delivered at seminar by Profs. Milton Konvitz, Neufeld, McKelvey, Cooke, Vernon Jensen, and Brooks
  - Students - ILR - Graduate - Administration, 1946-1966 (Box 26, Folder 29-32)
    MFN's appointment and eventual resignation as chairman of MILR examinations [1/66], memo from MFN to Prof. Robert Raimon proposing changing MILR exam requirements from a written examination to a research paper [12/2/65], report criticizing quality of MILR student performance and recommending changes [2/4/58], memo from MFN to Prof. R.H. Ferguson criticizing written and oral questioning in the MILR exams [2/3/58], corres from MFN to Prof. John Brophy recommending changes in MILR program [4/3/56], routine correspondence, tests, and evaluations
  - Students - ILR - Graduate - Administration, 1967-1973 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    Routine correspondence and reports.
  - Students - ILR - Graduate - Advisees, 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    Memos re graduate special committees.
  - Students ILR Graduate Applications, 1959-1979 (Box 26, Folder 35-37)
    Routine Correspondence
  - Students - ILR Graduate Assistantships, 1947-1968 (Box 26, Folder 38-42)
    Routine correspondence. Graduate assistant evaluations
  - Students ILR Graduate Assistantships, 1968-1976 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    Routine Correspondence and graduate assistant evaluations
  - Students ILR Graduate Council, 1953-1973 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Routine correspondence and booklets.
  - Students ILR Graduate Exchange, 1963-1966 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Routine correspondence re Soviet and U.S. students exchange program.
  - Students ILR Graduate Fellowships, 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Routine correspondence re the Dorothy Funt Memorial Scholarship. Includes newspaper clippings
  - Students ILR Undergraduate Applications, 1958-1975 (Box 27, Folder 7-8)
  - Students ILR Undergraduate Government, 1951-1976 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    New accounts of MFN's receival of the Excellence in Teaching Award presented by ILR student government [9/7/76], MFN's agreement with a plan to establish an ILR Standing Committee on Student Activities [3/5/51]. Minutes and resolutions of the ILR Student Organization meeting discussing the Building Service Employees efforts to unionize [12/4/50], and routine correspondence
  - Students ILR Undergraduate Research Assistants, 1966-1972 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Taft, Philip Correspondence Contributions, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 11-14)
    General Routine corrspondence re fundraising for the Philip Taft Labor History Award, chaired by MFN. Includes receipts and contributor lists
  - Taft, Philip Correspondence I, 1946-1971 (Box 27, Folder 15-20)
    Corres from Taft to MFN re Prof. Mark Perlman's criticisms of Taft's "Reflections on Selig Perlman as a Teacher and Writer" [4/24/76], MFN's recommendation and Taft's proposal to Guggenheim Foundation re a fellowhship for Taft to study the labor movement in Alabama [11/20/75], corres from MFN to Taft commenting on Taft's Rights of Union Members and the Government [3/26/75], corres from MFN to Taft offering criticism of Taft's article "Professor Perlman's Ideas and Activities" [9/1S/74], memo from Prof. James 0. Morris to MFN opposing the appointment of Taft to head a documentary project in industrial relations history at NYSSILR [2/7/69], corres from MFN to Taft re a two-year appointment to NYSSILR [5/16/68], ruling by Taft, acting for the first time as an impartial umpire for AFL-CIO, in favor of a claim by the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers against the Communications Workers of America [Rec'd by MFN 5/13/64], preliminary copy of Taft's Organized Labor in American History with MFN's corrections [10/4/63], MFN's recommendation and Taft's proposal to the Social Science Research Council re a fellowship for Taft to study labor relations in the theater industry [10/23/61], memo from C.A. Hanson to MFN re faculty input in the selection of the University President [3/2/60], Taft to MFN re the death of Selig Perlman and MFN's response [9/25/59], MFN to Ordway Tead, Vice President of Harper & Brothers, praising Taft's The AFL from the Death of Gompers to the Merger [3/27/59], corres from MFN to Taft re first chapters of Italy; School for Awakening Countries [12/1/1958], corres from MFN to Taft suggesting changes in Taft's lecture "An Overall Look at Racketeering in the Labor Movement" [10/2/57], report by MFN recommending Taft for a grant from the Social Science Research Council [2/23/54], corres from MFN to Taft re the publication of The House of Labor and comments on a Taft manuscript [2/19/51], corres from MFN to Taft re Building Service Employees strike [12/6/50], corres from Taft to MFN explaining decision not to accept a summer position at Cornell and remarking on campaign of Herbert Lehman [10/29/49], corres from Taft to MFN re devaluation of the British pound and its effect on labor and politics [9/20/49], corres from Taft to MFN re the state of their profession [3/23/49], corres from Taft to MFN re United States foreign policy [undated, c. 1947], corres from Taft to MFN re the Congress of Industrial Organizations [9/20/46], corres from MFN to Taft re the quality of Cornell students [9/6/46], corres from Taft to MFN re comparing Cornell, Brown and the University of Wisconsin [7/2/46], corres from MFN to Taft re his first impressions of Cornell and his preparations to begin teaching [6/25/46], routine and personal correspondence. Includes memorial booklets and newspaper clippings
  - Taft, Philip - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 21-24)
    Corres from MFN to Louis Starr, Director of Oral History Research Office at Columbia University, recommending oral memoirs of Margaret Hooper and Samuel D. Berger [7/18/77], newspaper copies reporting posthumous award of doctor of laws to Philip Taft (with citation enclosed) C&/6/77], copy of letter from President Howard Swearer of Brown to Theresa Taft, wife of Philip Taft, notifying her of honorary degree [5/19/77], minutes of Editorial Board of Labor History, meeting 4/13/77, and discussing, most notably, a memorial Taft issue to be edited by MFN [5/2/77], corres from George Meany, president of AFL-CIO, accepting appointment to the Fund Committee of the Philip Taft Labor History Award [5/2/77], personal memo from MFN detailing efforts to appoint George Meany to the Taft Fund Committee [4/29/77], statement describing Philip Taft Labor History Award [4/19/77], MFN to Gladys Feig, Labor History, outlining proposed tribute to Taft in that journal [4/15/77], Edwin Young, chancellor of the University of Wisconsin, agreeing to serve on the Taft Fund Board [4/11/77], memo from MFN to Arthur Devlin, Asst. University Counsel of Cornell, recommending the establishment of the Taft Fund (this proposal became the basis for subsequent drafts of Fund proposals) [3/30/77, memo from James 0. Morris to MFN expressing concerns over proposed Taft project [3/28/77], corres from MFN to Kathleen Imhoff, Wisconsin State Dept. of Public Instruction, to Selig Silverman re the desire of the AFL/CIO-ALA Joint Committee on Library Services to manage the Taft Memorial Award (enclosed is MFN's response) [3/25/77], personal memo by MFN detailing Theresa Taft's involvement in proposed Taft Award project [2/17/77], corres from MFN to Jerome Stein, professor at Brown Univ., re early conversations about the establishment of a Taft memorial fund and MFN's recommendations about the fund [2/11/77], corres from Imhoff to Silverman re ALA policy of establishing new awards [1/14/77], personal memo from MFN re proposal for Taft Labor History Award, including plans to ensure tax deductibility by finding an institution to establish the Fund at [1/4/77], corres from Theresa Taft to MFN re a biography written by Phil Taft [?1-2/77], corres from Theresa Taft to MFN re speech made by Phil Taft upon election by Pembroke College as "Favorite Professor" of the Class of '47 [?1-2/77], personal and routine correspondence
  - Taft, Philip - Correspondence - III, 1977-1980 (Box 27, Folder 25-29)
    Corres from Myron Kolatch, Secretary of Tamiment Institute, to MFN re decision of Tamiment board not to make further contributions to Taft fund [3/26/80], corres from James 0. Morris to MFN re the awarding of David M. Katzman's Seven Days a Week; Women and Domestic Service in Industrializing America the first Philip Taft Award [8/30/79], corres from Prof. Gary M. Fink, Georgia State University, to Theresa Taft re the editing of Phil Taft's History of Labor in Alabama [2/26/79], corres from MFN to Daniel Leab re organization of Philip Taft memorial edition of Labor History [1/4/78], corres from MFN to George Meany re total contributions to Taft fund [9/27/77], corres from MFN to George Borts, Brown Univ., re Borts's memorial of Taft [9/21/77], corres from MFN to George Meany re receipt of AFL-CIO contribution to Taft fund [9/20/77], routine and personal correspondence.
  - Taft, Philip - Correspondence - IV, 1980-1982 (Box 27, Folder 30-31)
    Corres from James 0. Morris to MFN re composition of Taft Award committee and possible conflicts of interest [8/3/82], corres from Clete Daniels to Morris expressing opinion that ILR faculty can be judged for Taft Award [7/19/82], corres from Sidney Fine to Morris re opinion that ILR faculty be excluded from consideration for Taft Award [7/6/82], Prof. Mel Dubofsky, SUNY Binghamton, re candidates for 1982 Taft Award [7/5/82], corres from Morris to Taft Award Committee members re qualifications for entry in 1982 competition and exclusion of ILR faculty from consideration [6/24/82], corres from MFN to Gary Fink re Fink's unpublished essay Philip Taft: Labor Scholar and Labor Activist (essay included) [10/3/80], routine and personal correspondence.
  - Taft, Philip - Labor History - Memorial Issue - I, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 32-34)
    Corres from MFN to Daniel J. Leab, Managing Editor of Labor History, re Columbia University Oral History memoirs of Philip Taft (includes copy of transcript) [9/6/77], corres from Theresa Taft to MFN re Phil Taft's earliest published works (includes photocopies of newspaper clippings) [?9/77], corres from MFN to Prof.David Brody suggesting changes in Brody's Philip Taft: Labor Scholar [7/22/77], routine and personal correspondence.
  - Taft, Philip - Labor History - Memorial Issue - II, 1977-1979 (Box 27, Folder 35-37)
  - Taft, Philip - Labor History - Memorial Issue - III, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 38-40)
    Corres from Phil Taft to Dan Lieb re material to be published in Labor History [rec'd by MFN 9/10/77], routine correspondence. Includes galleys and copy of Winter, 1978 issue of Labor History.
  - Taft, Philip - Oral History - Columbia (Box 28, Folder 1-8)
    Includes a copy of 1977 Reminiscences of Philip Taft, edited, revised and indexed by MFN, one edited and revised by Theresa Taft, and the original unedited version of the memoirs
  - Wallen (Saul) Memorial Fund, 1970-1985 (Box 28, Folder 9-12)
    Booklets, committee minutes, and routine correspondence
  - Weinberg Seminar - Correspondence, 1961-1979 (Box 28, Folder 13-18)
    Memo from Robert Risley to Weinberg Seminar Steering Committee (MFN a member) re committee meeting of June 4 [6/7/65], minutes of 1964 Planning Committee for Weinberg Seminar (MFN a member) [5/22/64], corres from Dean John W. Mcconnell to MFN re future labor-management seminars [1/23/63], corres from James C. Evans, Counsellor, Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Manpower, to MFN re impact of 1962 Weinberg Seminar proceedings [1/7/63], Wilhelm Weinberg Foundation press release (includes photographs of Weinberg) [10/5/62], corres from Dean Mcconnell to Richard Netter re MFN's agreeing to serve as co-chairman of 1962 Weinberg Seminar [5/22/62], corres from Leonard P. Aries, vice president of the National Conference on Christians and Jews, to MFN re plans for 1962 Weinberg Seminar [5/21/61], programs and routine correspondence concerning especially the 1962 Weinberg Seminar. Includes newspaper clippings and a photograph at end of file
  - Weinberg Seminar Programs and Speakers, 1962-1976 (Box 28, Folder 19-21)
    Corres from Irving Bluestone, Assistant to the President, UAW, to MFN re Bluestone's 1962 Weinberg Seminar statement (statement enclosed) [11/13/62], routine correspondence. Includes programs and schedules of seminars, especially 1962 seminar
  - Wertheimer, Barbara, 1975-1984 (Box 28, Folder 22-25)
    Notes re the organization, format and funding of the Barbara Wertheimer Woman Worker Documentation Project [2/22/84], remembrance of Wertheimer by MFN at Conference on Women and Labor Market Policy [10/5/83], corres from MFN to Wertheimer re her reception of a Ford Foundation grant [10/27/81], Wertheimer's proposal to the Ford Foundation [6/4/81], a similar proposal to the National Endowment for the Humanities [5/81], corres from Wertheimer to MFN re recommendations for grants for Our Century. Our Time; The Story of Working Women. 1914 to the Present [5/22/81], corres from Wertheimer to MFN re a sequel to We Were There: The Story of Working Women in America. 1609-1914 [9/22/78],corres from MFN to Prof. Donald E. Cullen recommending Wertheimer for the position of Associate Professor in the Extension Division of the NYSSILR [11/4/76], corres from MFN to Wertheimer re suggestions concerning the conclusion of We Were There [1/29/76], corres from MFN to Wertheimer re suggestions concerning the first ten chapters of We Were There [10/14/75], routine and personal correspondence. Includes news clippings and programs
  - Williams, C. Brian (former PhD student) -Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 28, Folder 26-27)
    Routine correspondence re Williams's PhD dissertation, examinations, and assistantships
  - Wyzanski, Charles, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    Corres from Neufeld to Wyzanski re Wyzanski's New York Times Tribute to Frances Perkins, copies of the tribute (original and revised.)
  - I, 1959-1982 (Box 28, Folder 29-32)
    Newsletters (The Xerox World, Manufacturing Digest), booklets (Shareholders Report), reports (includes histories of Xerox and "Motivational Constraints in an Industrial Retraining Program"), newspaper clippings.
  - II, 1962-1987 (Box 28, Folder 33-37)
    Corres from MFN to Prof. Sanford Jacoby, UCLA, re the history of unionism at Xerox (includes newspaper clippings) [3/30/87], memo from MFN re election of new officers at Xerox [8/14/86], newsletters, booklets, newspaper clippings
  - YWCA, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 38)
- Series II. XEROX FILES
  - Organization and Personnel, 1955-1963 (Box 29, Folder 1-6)
    Organization manuals of Xerox Corporation at Rochester, reports of company employee manpower, news releases reporting the elections of new officers
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1950-1957 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    Corres re contracts and contract negotiations at Rochester Xerox (negotiations held by Xerox personnel management and ACWU, representing Xerox workers). Includes 1954 labor agreement.
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 8-11)
    Corres re 1958 contract, copy of labor agreement, reports of labor grievances.
  - Contracts, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 12-19)
    Minutes of contract negotiating meetings, memos from William Asher, Manager of Industrial Relations at Rochester Xerox, and D.S. Raub, Asst. Vice President, Personnel Relations at Rochester Xerox, re Company and Union meetings in 1959. These meetings addressed primarily grievances and personnel problems.
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 20-28)
    Minutes of contract negotiating meetings at Rochester, copy of 1960 labor agreement, memos from Asher and Raub re labor-management meetings, grievances, and employee discipline.
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 29-42)
    Memos from Asher and Raub re labor management meetings at Rochester, addressing primarily grievances and plant consolidation. Also includes the 1961 report detailing reasons for and effects of consolidation at the Rochester Haloid Street Plant (folder 38 contains guide to report.)
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 43-56)
    contract negotiation material (includes suggestions and memos), memos from D.S. Raub to J.C. Wilson, President and General Manager of Xerox, re preparations for 1962 labor negotiations, minutes of contract negotiation meetings and sub-committee meetings between Company and Union, analysis of Union membership vote on contract, copy of 1962 labor agreement, memos regarding Company-Union grievance meetings at Rochester.
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 1-15)
    Report from Asher to Wilson re upcoming negotiations of 1964 contract and recommending certain strategies [6/63], minutes of contract negotiation meetings, memo from Asher re settlement of contract negotiations [12/17/63], outline of proposed profit sharing plan [1/13/64], memos from Asher re general Company-Union meetings [five meetings held between 8/27/62 and 9/5/62, discussing status of various company projects and programs], memos re grievance, shop, and disciplinary meetings
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 16-29)
    Memos from J.T. Wigg re sub-committee of Xerox and Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (A.C.W.A.) representatives meeting to reach a final agreement on language proposed in major contract negotiation meetings, memos from Wigg re contract negotiations with International Union of Operating Engineers (I.U.O.E.), corres from Wilson to Bud Miller, A.C.W.A. representative, re revision of 30-day new employee probationary period [5/25/64], copy of 1964 labor agreement between Xerox and A.C.W.A. [8/3/64], memos from Wigg re general Company-Union meetings that clarified contract language, discussed grievance procedure and incentive plans, gave business outlook, and introduced new products, memos re grievance meetings, negotiations of 1964 Shop Chairman Agreement [4/10/64], meetings re assembly line slowdown [5/22/64], and disciplinary meetings.
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 30-39)
    Minutes of Company-Union meetings re grievances, discipline, and routine business.
  - Contracts - Grievances, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 40-54)